This is how the odds are looking for
[music] the player who will be named the
winner. Seems like Harry Kane is the
favorite, but Lamin and Killian Mbappe
are close behind, [music]
but it does seem like this year the
voting can be quite unpredictable. We've
got a lot of a lot of players in the mix
compared to recent years where it's
[music] just been one of two players who
we think are going to win. Uh you could
make the case for honestly, look, one of
five players there. [music] So that's
what we're going to be doing, making the
case um who we think is going to win the
Ballindor this year. Loo, do you want to
get us started? Who you making the case
for? Yeah, look, I'm going to go with
Lamine Yamal. And I know Madrid fans
won't want to hear this. I know that
there's some other fans, maybe Abui fans
will want to hear this because their
team knocked out Barcelona. And maybe
some other fans who watched the World
Cup and thought, "Okay, maybe Rodri
should be more in the conversation." But
Lameal is an absolute genius. And if
you've watched Barcelona, especially
since this season started, he looks to
be the Lummenal from the previous
campaign that we saw dazzle the entire
world and we were talking about against
Inter looking very much like the best
player in the world. He's only 19 years
old and to look at the insane numbers
that he's put up 2020 in terms of 20
goals minimum, 20 plus assists is
insane. the number of injuries that
happened to Rafinia, Pedri being out
last campaign. I'm gonna put even
Frankie Dong and Robert Leandowski being
out for Barcelona. I think that impacted
him, but he's not shy of shouldering the
burden. Hannah, and for Balandor worthy
and Ballindor level players, you have to
take responsibility. He's the face of
Barcelona. He's the pride of Barcelona.
And I think that he has a strong say in
the Ballindor. And of course, he's a
World Cup winner as well. And even
though it didn't show in the goals and
assists, his performances later in the
tournament, they're there for the taken.
>> Yeah. And last year it was really
between Lamin and Usman Dembele as well.
He came so close to getting it, but
Dembele won it. Jeff, who have you got
taken the case for?
>> Well, I think there's two subjects here.
Who I think should win it and who I
think will win it.
>> Um, pretty much the same thing to a
degree. I mean, the book is you don't
get that sort of difference in that. Do
you see those odds? Kane minus 162. All
the others are plus.
>> So the book is they've already voted
where they think the journals are going
with this. But what's interesting is
yes, Harry Kane had a phenomenal season
last season both for club and country.
His average was a goal every 72 minutes.
So hitting a goal a game is ridiculous
in the league. 61 in 51. He got a total
of 72. He got 12 in 14 for England. But
normally the balandor goes to a player
who's either won Champions League, the
World Cup, the Euros, copper America,
something of that ilk. But there have
been exceptions. You look back Messi
2010, he scored 60 goals. So this was my
thinking. Will they give it to a player
who hasn't won a major prize in this
particular year? It also happened with
Ronaldo and it happened a second time
with Messi as well. So I think given
Kane's phenomenal phenomenal return of
goals, I think he'll win it and I think
he is a deserving winner for it as well.
>> Mhm.
>> Killing Mbappé and I'm going to go
against the grain that it's not as much
about trophies for him, but it's about
simply being the best player in the
world. He had an off year with Real
Madrid, 43 goals, 86 goals in two
seasons with Real Madrid. And those were
considered him not at his best, the team
not at his best. But I think that when
we saw him with the France in the n in
the World Cup and we saw him happy and
smiling and combining with his
teammates, we saw the best player in the
world once again and reminded that it is
in fact Killian Mbappé. He can do it on
an off year. He did it at the biggest
stage in the World Cup. So I'm going to
go with the best player in the world,
Killian Mbappe.
>> Are you saying he's a better striker
than Harry Kane?
>> I think he's the best player in the
world.
>> No. Is he a better striker than Harry
Kane?
>> Yes.
>> I see a future I see a future segment. I
just think as well he's top scorer in
the World Cup, Champions League, and in
this league.
>> Let me just Do you think goals in La
Liga equal goals in the Bundesliga?
>> There there there's a little bit of a
difference there, isn't there?
>> Well, yes. One's a two team league. The
other one is a
>> But it's a better quality league
overall.
>> Are you surprised, [music] by the way,
G, that Harry Kane is such a heavy
favorite to win it?
>> Yeah, I am because uh like Troy was
mentioning off camera, every single one
has a flaw in [music] in why they're on
this list. You know, it's not the days
of Ronaldo and Messi where you're like,
"Okay, there's really you can't poke
hard to argue against it."
>> Here, every single player on the list
you can argue against. You know, for me,
it would have been an easy one if Yamal
actually played to his capacity at the
World Cup. He didn't. He had a really
know he came in with an injury, but
didn't didn't have a really good World
Cup. Rodri had a good World Cup, but
didn't play the entire year.
>> Harry Kane let you down a little bit in
the World Cup, right, for England.
Didn't pop up in the biggest of moments.
What about for Bayern Munich in the
biggest of moments? He scored a
consolation goal in some of those games.
So nobody gives you feels a little
dirty. No matter who wins, it feels
dirty.
>> Do you feel the same way, Troy?
>> Yeah, absolutely. And again, if you're
going to go on goals, let's say that
that's a criteria. I don't really know
what the criteria is to be honest. If
you say it's goals and you go Harry Kane
for that reason, when Mbappe can turn
around and say, well, I was the golden
boot for the World Cup, golden boot in
La Liga, golden boot in Champions
League. So
>> to me, where am I? To me, should be the
favorite.
>> It just feels weird. And to Greta's
point, it is a little bit based on, you
know, what what's your what's your
poison essentially? Why are we choosing
this? For me, I think it should be lin
based on past seasons again. What have
you won? Won the biggest tournament in
um
>> World Cup World Cup. Obviously, the
Euros doesn't come into this for for the
year. It doesn't come into ultimately
he's won everything. Remember the year
when Rodri won it, which people question
it came in the big tournament kind of
played more extra points. This would
have to be the same thing. I I don't
know. I I agree. No matter which one
wins it and then also one name that's
not even on there, Drew Bellingham's not
even on there. Had an unbelievable World
Cup.
>> So true.
>> So again, I don't I don't really know is
the honest
>> but they haven't even won La Liga and
they haven't competed. Well, this
everyone's got a hole in the argument.
What about Kavaria?
>> Yeah,
>> is you could say hands down player ball
at the feet most fun player to watch,
most effective player. Two champions
leagues in two years. Simple fact that
Georgia doesn't play in the World Cup
docks him so many points.
>> And also we're saying that no one really
shone in the World Cup that's leading
the way for the Balon.
>> If we're going to do that Ruiz needs to
be in it.
>> Fabian Ruiz.
>> Fabian Ruiz won all three tournaments
and won the World Cup.
>> I'm not a big fan.
>> I know. But I'm saying again to that
point, you know,
>> no one knows the criteria. That's the
biggest point of it.
>> The Ballindor sadly has become a
popularity contest more than anything
else cuz back in our days it used to be,
oh, that is the best player in the
world. You can't deny when you talk
about talents that have won it
>> like trophies aside based on talent.
>> It was that's what it was. And obviously
yes coming to the part that these best
players did play for the biggest teams
and win Champions League and win
different things. But nowadays I think
it's become more of a popularity contest
and there's a little bit of politics
that plays well with it. And I I agree
with everything that G said. Whoever
wins it, you can have an argument of why
they shouldn't have won it and why
someone else should have. I personally
would not be surprised if Laminar wins
it. I I think that he probably will win
it in what he's done and the next face
off.
>> Will he be your pick?
>> You mean your mom?
>> I would have to say yeah. I'd have to
say yeah. And I look at more than
anything else his age. He played in the
World Cup. Yes, he wasn't great, but he
still won the World Cup. That's the
thing. And he played in every single he
played every single league as well and
he's won the league as well. Barcelona
and at the age that he's done what he's
done.
>> I think it will probably
>> he's so exciting to watch. That's the
other thing I test
>> like you could you could say he's the
best player like when you watch Kabad
you could say that Yamal you could say
that Messi another all these guys won
>> Dembele I don't know Demell is one of
those ones that was in the right right
team at the right time and obviously has
all the tools but look this is uh and
even for you take the world take the
World Cup out of it no it's 45 goal
involvements 25 goals 20 assists and won
the World Cup and won the league
>> in that year so it's like
>> this past weekend they said he's come
this past weekend they said [music] he's
come back to his best. He come played
against Valencia. He's absolutely
phenomenal. He's he's a player that like
Troy likes to say gets you on the edge
of your seats. That's just the reality
of it. When you watch Lemi Yamal, he
knows that people are talking about him
going to watch him. He's not scared of
that stage. He goes out there and
performs. Some people might say he's
cocky or he's overconfident, but there's
a there's a real thin line between
confidence and arrogance. And I think
for me, what he does and everything he's
done, I would say he's the one I vote
for. Because you look back at the World
Cup, didn't start the first game, didn't
go too well for for Spain. People
starting to question Spain, their
credit. Then after that, he played every
single game for Spain. They go on to win
the World Cup. And I think for me that
he will be the one that wins it and
should win it.
>> Okay. So you've got Lumi Yamal. What
about you, girl? You going the same way?
>> I think like Troy said, if you look at
all of it, Yamal, you think about his
World Cup. For me, it's Yumal andb. It's
hard to argue against leading goal
scorer Champions League, leading goal
scorer, the World Cup, and leading goal
scorer of La Liga. I mean, how can you
make an argument against that? That's
really difficult.
>> Here [snorts] you go. I mean, 57
appearances, 58 goals.
>> That's insane.
>> And by the way, he's not playing on the
playground in the backyard. He's this
playing against the best teams in the
world, some of the best defenders in the
world constantly. So,
>> I get it. Even for Mbappe, it feels a
little dirty because they haven't won La
Liga and they didn't win the World Cup
in the [music] biggest moment. But
>> Champions League,
>> this this goes to your argument because
Barcelona won La Liga and then Lamar was
there and then he wins the World Cup
with Spain. So there's so many different
things you can look at where people
argue with that to say cuz France didn't
win the World Cup.
>> It's just going to be Messi either way.
It's going to be messy in which they
vote no more.
No, even even it's [laughter] going to
be messy. But even though Messi's on the
list, Messi's on the 30 list. So, you
know, again, in that regard, but it will
be a messy situation because if Harry
Kane wins it, the argument will be, "Oh,
but he didn't have a great World Cup,
for example, or if Mbappe wins it. Oh,
he's got great stats, but he didn't do
this." So, there's always going to be
this counter argument. So, no matter who
wins it in this situation,
>> there's going to be someone I had Lein.
>> Lemal. You're going
>> Mbappe.
>> Mbappe. Now,
>> say like you mean it.
>> I mean, we say we don't like it, but
>> I'm going I'm going
>> the You know, Europe and the world
doesn't like the English. It's got no
chance.
>> True. [music] There are a lot of names
on there that are deserving, but there
are also some that really stand out,
right?
>> Yeah. I mean, especially if you look at
the the bookies favorites as to who's
going to win this trophy. You would see
that there's clearly one player who has
an advantage right now. And why would
you bet against that player and that
player being Harry Kane with the goals
that he's scored, the performances he
put out there, you have to say you're a
bit crazy if you go against these types
of odds. This tells me that the bookies
know something that we don't. I actually
broke it down to the percentage as well.
It is 63.6%
probability that he's going to actually
lift that trophy. And why would you bet
against it? Of course, listen, we're
here in an entertainment business and he
is the guy who's scoring the most goals
above anybody else right now across
obviously multiple competitions for
Bayern Munich. Let's focus on that
alone. It is 61 goals in 51 Bayern
games. That's what we're looking at for
the London door states or stats and his
status. I do think that when you look at
what he did for do for England during
the World Cup, it's also truly
exceptional. and he's someone who's
taken his form from what he did
domestically into that World Cup and
almost led the three lines to a real
triumphant tournament. But there's no
real competitor as far as I'm concerned.
I understand it. Trophies tell you a big
story here. Spain had a tremendous
amount of success. Very happy for Amin,
very happy for Rodri, but Harry Kane is
on a a world of his own. If you look at
what he did doing in the 51 games, it's
1.20 goals per games an average. That is
on another planet, Alex. Sick. So, he
must be your favorite as well.
>> He's my favorite. He is. Tell me why. I
mean, well, you already talked about
alluded to the goals. 73 goals is that's
insane. Like, [music] that is production
that you just don't see very often. So,
yes, winning the domestic treble. I like
that. [music] What puts him over the top
for me is you love to look at stats,
right? Everybody wants to see how many
goals, how many assists, how many goals
created. what he has done to reinvent
himself inside that bar that um Bayern
Munich system that
>> Why did you say reinvent himself though?
Because he was already very good at
Tottenham. So why did you say reinvent
himself?
>> Because I love the way that sometimes he
would track back and help defensively.
He changed based Sure. But I think he's
making more of an impact now, especially
because Byron is such a team that is uh
>> looking for, you know, bigger trophies.
I mean Tottenham wasn't really a team
that was going to bring home a potential
Champions League.
>> Tottenham weren't good enough. They
weren't good enough to win a Champions
League. Bayern Munich is a team that
could win the Champions League. I mean,
you finished just short of the winner in
the semi-finals by a goal. Yes, you are
a team that can win the Champions
League. And the impact there is
different than the impact that you can
have at Tottenham.
>> Listen, I think his goals and his
statistics are what's going to get him
the Bond door. Nothing else. I think
he's the same player as he was at
Tottenham. He played in the Premier
League and obviously it was very
difficult to score goals there. He
scored a phenomenal amount of goals for
Tottenham football club. It was
ridiculous what he did do for that
football club except didn't win a
trophy. He went to Bayern Munich in my
personal opinion to get ready for a
World Cup to be able to extend his
career longer and to be able to
potentially win a Bond door and a World
Cup with England. What he did do for
England in the World Cup, it was seven
games, six goals, that's exceptional
after the season he had for Bayern
Munich. It's absolutely no joke what he
did do. And I think you're starting to
see the respect that he's getting from
Kilan Abbappa Ma Pedri all these other
players who are being asked Kiche about
who they think's going to win Bondor.
Everyone says Harry Kane. Now, I respect
the performance, but we've always seen
the same from him. He drops off, he
plays these passes, his assists are in
incredible as well, but it's the goal
scoring. It's the stats that go into it.
He just broke an England all-time goal
scoring record at World Cups. He is
doing something that other players
haven't done. He's taken a chance by
going to another league away from the
Premier League. And he's an Englishman
to do that. Why? I mean, listen, right
now, if you were to look at the best
players in world football, you'd have to
say the majority of them don't play in
the Premier League. Mhm.
>> The majority of them play elsewhere. And
why is to do exactly what Harry Kane's
just done. He knew he could score more
goals in the Bundesliga. Why the
Bundesliga? Because it's the league with
the highest goals per game ratio. Why
Bayern Munich? Because they clean the
floor with absolutely every opponent
they play against. Bayern are delighted
he's there. He's the main man at that
football club 100%. But he's got to win
the big trophy there. You can't just go
there and win abalone and be happy with
that. Harry Kane, I think, personally,
is more interested in winning a
Champions League trophy with Bayern
Munich and cleaning up domestically than
he is winning a Bond door. The decision
to go to Germany and play in the
Bundesliga is what's going to get him
hands-on trophy with that Bond door. And
also what he did do in a threeline
jersey, which hurts me to say being
someone who was raised in Scotland.
>> Well, talk about uh trophies. Killing
Mbappé coming up short, you know, for
the last couple of years. But here is
the thing with Killian Abbapp because
when you look at the numbers, you want
to look at the numbers. He outscored
Harry Kane in the World Cup. He
outscored him in Champions League as
well. He won the golden boot in both of
[music] them. Make a case for Killian
Mbappé. Well, he scored 11 less than
obviously Harry Kane did. So that's
where Harry Kane gets the odds and
that's where the odds lean in his favor.
Killian Mbappé is a phenomenal player.
Obviously has an enormous case because
he was top goal scorer in La Liga as you
pointed out there, top goal scorer in
the Champions League. That is no joke.
That statistically gives him the
opportunity to to be successful. The 10
goals at the World Cup was was
unbelievable. It's 22 now he scored in
his career at the World Cup. He is going
to win many many doors and he should
potentially win this one. I mean having
the golden boot obviously in La Liga is
one thing to Pici but no trophy to
follow suit is maybe a bit of a
disappointment. I think he would have
more of a debate, more of an argument
had France gone all the way and beaten
Spain and got to that World Cup final
and won it. then you have a better case,
a better argument because you're not far
away. Statistically, it's exceptional.
But we've also critiqued Kenbappy for
what he did do for Real Madrid this past
season. The goals are one thing, the
performances and sometimes missing
penalty kicks and big moments where he
missed opportunities. That's not
forgotten when it comes to awards like
this, individual awards. It's more about
consistency over the years. And it's
crazy for me to say that with how many
goals he scored. He is one hell of a
player, right? 25 goals in La Liga, 15
obviously in the Champions League and 10
in the World Cup. When I say those
numbers, I feel silly by saying this guy
shouldn't win a Bond door, but
unfortunately for him, Harry Kane's in
the race.
>> How close do you think it is? Is this
one and two in your mind or does a guy
like Leaminium all factor into that as
well?
>> I think Rodri's win of the Bond door
tells us that we should expect the
unexpected when it comes to this
competition. I know Venicious Jr. was
probably hard done by because of his
outgoing and statistical season that he
had at Real Madrid and what he did do
obviously win uh the Champions League
with Real Madrid that season. Um but I
do think that winning the World Cup does
have an impact on it. I think we've seen
that clearly with Lion Messi winning so
many. Of course, he did do incredibly
well at Barcelona and then he's done
well at PSG. He's done well at Miami.
But at the same time, I think that this
is going to be a one-horse race. It's
not a three-horse race. You can throw
Lamin's hat into that, but he's more of
a team player for Spain during the World
Cup than he was an individual player.
And I think this is an individual ward
and it comes down to statistics and
consistency. And I think Lemma, I'm
going to throw this out there. He will
win belond the war many times. But at
the same time, his statistics need to up
a notch. He's been that guy who's got
himself into a position where he's got
close to 20 goals, 20 assists all season
long. Last season, it was incredible,
right? He had a 25 goals, 20 assists
season. That's phenomenal. But I still
think it can be better for me. And if it
is better, he starts to creep into the
Leonol Messi category of player. Maybe
I'm crazy by saying that, but he's
surrounded by talented players at
Barcelona Spain. He's only 19 years old.
I mean, and you look at what he did
leading the teenage gold contributions
in Champions League. His day is coming.
I am with you, though. It's not this
year.
>> He's 19. Think about how many more
opportunities he's going to have. He's a
generational player and I think we are
going to see that. Any dark horse car
characters that you think might come out
of the way. The the one that jumps out
to me is Kakar Skelia because if you
watch him, he has an impact on every
single match that he plays. But maybe
you could argue, okay, you know, the
numbers aren't exactly there. In
Champions League, they were though. He
was exceptional and most of that action
coming in the knockout stages when his
team needed him the most.
>> Well, you asked the question and took
the answer. I mean, Kaviche is the one
player. I mean, that's the truth. He is
the one player that probably stands out.
Rodri might be the other one who's
deserved of a shout because of what he
did during the World Cup, but I don't
think he was as good at this World Cup
as he was in the Euros when they won it
and also what he did do for Manchester
City at that period of time. Um, Kiche
is unbelievable. His numbers don't lie,
but there's room for improvement with
him. PSG winning the Champions League
back to back is truly exceptional. I
will say this, Alex, the reason why I
think PSG have cleaned up is because of
his arrival. remember he came through a
winter transfer and actually transformed
that PSG season. They they had to go
through the playoffs twice and he's one
of the reasons why they got to a
Champions League final. These stats
don't lie. Again, I go back to what
we're seeing with Lamin. Not a striker.
So, it's very difficult to have those
types of numbers. Harry Kane and
obviously the Leandowskis who didn't
win, but the same time the Messes and
the Ronaldos, they're not all out and
out strikers, right? So, I want to see
better numbers from these players and I
think Fiche playing a little bit more
domestically will help him improve his
statistics and improve his chances of
eventually going on to win it. What
hurts him though is his national team
which I don't like. It should be judged
by his performance, how much you
entertain us. That's what Bolognor is to
me. It's about the entertainment factor
and not necessarily all the stats. But
right now, as you will see, Harry Kane's
going to win this because of the stats.
>> Harry Kane, I think we are both uh in
agreement. It's it's his it's his and
it's happening in London which is really
cool. That that's going to be awesome to
watch. But Harry Kane, you look at the
numbers in whatever way you slice them.
This guy was the absolute man this year
for both club and country. Phil, talk to
me about Lamin. It seems like in the
last, let's say, three weeks or so, he's
just gone to another level. That's seven
goals now in his last four matches.
Lucas, this is a kid. I can't believe
I'm saying a kid because he's playing
like he's been at the club for about 15
seasons now.
>> Yeah, it's over 150 appearances for uh
Barcelona and he is just 19. It's it's
it's quite ridiculous what he's doing
today. He scored um and you know a
couple of goals and I think it's
interesting that Rafinia let him take
the penalty because Rafinho usually
takes the penalties for Barcelona but he
gave it to Lem and why did he give it to
Lemine? Well, everybody's talking about
the Balonor and it does help when your
candidate is is scoring goals and
another couple of goals for Lamin Yamal
today won't have hurt at all. There's
actually an interview he's given to
Spanish TV. some of the extracts of it
are coming out tonight in the in the
Spanish press and Lemine himself has
said um me and Kian Mbappe we're
probably the two best players in the
world but you know I think this year I
deserve the balonor so he's doing the
campaigning himself but he's also doing
it by scoring goals and it's true you
know at the World Cup we didn't
necessarily see him shine maybe we saw
him play a slightly different role but
at the start of this season the first
game he was a little bit discreet
against Elchshire but apart from that
he's been absolutely flying looking
confident doing brilliant things
consistently and scoring goals as well.
You know, six league goals after just
five games. He scored 16 in the whole of
last season. He's well on track um to go
a lot better than